<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Fake Control]]></title>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-12T14:06:01+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://fakecontrol.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Fake Control Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About «Order of the Russian Federation Government»]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/12/ob-ukazah-pravitelstva-rf/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T14:06:01+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/12/ob-ukazah-pravitelstva-rf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one of the shortest posts ever: order № 303/14р, allegedly signed by Medvedev on March 1, <em>does not exist</em> in the <a href="http://government.consultant.ru">database</a> of &ldquo;Regulatory Documents of the Russian Federation Government&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/BNMzvzt.png" alt="303/14-fake" /></p>

<p>Translation of the image above:</p>

<blockquote><p>Government of the Russian Federation
Order from March 1, 2014 № 303/14р</p>

<p>Moscow</p>

<p>Agree on a draft of a state program for Trans-Baikal, Kamchatka and Primorye Territories about the &ldquo;Assistance in resettlement to Trans-Baikal, Kamchatka, and the Primorsky Region of compatriots currently residing in the new subjects of the Russian Federation, in particular, in the Autonomous Republic of Crimea, Odessa, Kherson, Nikolae, Donetsk, Luhansk and Kharkiv regions for 2014-2016 years&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Prime Minister of the Russian Federation
Dmitry Medvedev</p></blockquote>

<p>You can make sure yourself by checking the search results for the March 1</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we've been doing during week?]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/07/digest/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-07T15:57:42+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/07/digest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Probably, you&rsquo;ve be working hard for the good of your country and didn&rsquo;t chill in social networks a lot. Unlike you, we were busy to sort out those news and prepare the following digest with the most famous, irregular and fake ones. Enjoy!</p>

<h3><a href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/03/2-girls-1-fake/">2 Girls, 1 Fake</a></h3>

<p>Two women, who cry constantly and blame &ldquo;radical&rdquo; forces for &ldquo;destruction&rdquo; of their dear ukrainian cities. We tried to investigate their identities and shared our understanding with you. Changing cities, names and stories on daily basis, these two had a fabulous tour around Ukraine. Also we&rsquo;ve got some very interesting comments from dentists and plastic surgeons.</p>

<h3><a href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/03/second-passport/">Second passport, Third Sentence</a></h3>

<p>This one is from our all time favourite &ndash; Russia Today. They&rsquo;ve recently reported that having dual citizenship in Ukraine may become punishable offence. We tried hard to overcome our hysterical laughter and managed to explain why this is not true.</p>

<h3><a href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/george-bush/">USS That Couldn&rsquo;t Make It</a></h3>

<p>A breathtaking story about adventures of George H. W. Bush aircraft carrier, which never managed to get to the Crimea and just chilled in Greece instead. Besides explaining what is what, we send greetings to the team of Ukrainian TV channel &ldquo;ICTV&rdquo; and suggest everybody to read &ldquo;Montreux Convention Regarding the Regime of the Straits&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s fun reading, we promise!</p>

<h3><a href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/IMF-debunk/">About IMF &ldquo;requirements&rdquo;</a></h3>

<p>Your parents must&rsquo;ve told you about crazy mortage payments and the disbandment of free education for your (hypothetical) kids. All that is IMF&rsquo;s fault! Except it&rsquo;s not and your parents were fooled. We discussed those fact a lot in our article. Anyway, are you really sure that you&rsquo;re ready to have kids?</p>

<h3><a href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/06/cyrillic-cancellation/">About Cyrillic script being &ldquo;cancelled&rdquo;</a></h3>

<p>Is it totally fine to post an information on one of the biggest news agencies site without even mention to reliable source? We did not think so too! Latin alphabet is no cakewalk to suddenly start to use, especially in a country which was using Cyrillic script for many centuries. Fun historical facts as Friday bonus!</p>

<hr />

<p>You can find more at our <a href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/">site</a> or <a href="https://www.facebook.com/fakecontrol.org">Facebook page</a>.</p>

<p>If you want to send us important news or just want to share a picture of a cute pug, <a href="https://twitter.com/fakecontrol_org">tweet us</a> or send us an <a href="team@fakecontrol.org">email</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About State department and Russian MFA]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/07/embassy/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-07T15:53:35+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/07/embassy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Department of State <a href="http://russian.moscow.usembassy.gov/factsheet-ukraine-03062014.html">published</a> a fact sheet disproving some of the statements Putin has made about Ukraine.</p>

<p>We decided to quote this list on our website as well:</p>

<blockquote><ol>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: Russian forces in Crimea are only acting to protect Russian military assets. It is “citizens’ defense groups,” not Russian forces, who have seized infrastructure and military facilities in Crimea.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: Strong evidence suggests that members of Russian security services are at the heart of the highly organized anti-Ukraine forces in Crimea. While these units wear uniforms without insignia, they drive vehicles with Russian military license plates and freely identify themselves as Russian security forces when asked by the international media and the Ukrainian military. Moreover, these individuals are armed with weapons not generally available to civilians.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: Russia’s actions fall within the scope of the 1997 Friendship Treaty between Ukraine and the Russian Federation.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: The 1997 agreement requires Russia to respect Ukraine’s territorial integrity. Russia’s military actions in Ukraine, which have given them operational control of Crimea, are in clear violation of Ukraine’s territorial integrity and sovereignty.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: The opposition failed to implement the February 21 agreement with former Ukrainian President Viktor Yanukovych.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: The February 21 agreement laid out a plan in which the Rada, or Parliament, would pass a bill to return Ukraine to its 2004 Constitution, thus returning the country to a constitutional system centered around its parliament. Under the terms of the agreement, Yanukovych was to sign the enacting legislation within 24 hours and bring the crisis to a peaceful conclusion. Yanukovych refused to keep his end of the bargain. Instead, he packed up his home and fled, leaving behind evidence of wide-scale corruption.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: Ukraine’s government is illegitimate. Yanukovych is still the legitimate leader of Ukraine.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: On March 4, President Putin himself acknowledged the reality that Yanukovych “has no political future.” After Yanukovych fled Ukraine, even his own Party of Regions turned against him, voting to confirm his withdrawal from office and to support the new government. Ukraine’s new government was approved by the democratically elected Ukrainian Parliament, with 371 votes – more than an 82% majority. The interim government of Ukraine is a government of the people, which will shepherd the country toward democratic elections on May 25th – elections that will allow all Ukrainians to have a voice in the future of their country.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: There is a humanitarian crisis and hundreds of thousands are fleeing Ukraine to Russia and seeking asylum.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: To date, there is absolutely no evidence of a humanitarian crisis. Nor is there evidence of a flood of asylum-seekers fleeing Ukraine for Russia. International organizations on the ground have investigated by talking with Ukrainian border guards, who also refuted these claims. Independent journalists observing the border have also reported no such flood of refugees.
(editor&rsquo;s note: we&rsquo;ve already <a href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/02/first_channel_geography/">covered</a> this issue)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: Ethnic Russians are under threat.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: Outside of Russian press and Russian state television, there are no credible reports of any ethnic Russians being under threat. The new Ukrainian government placed a priority on peace and reconciliation from the outset. President Oleksandr Turchynov refused to sign legislation limiting the use of the Russian language at regional level. Ethnic Russians and Russian speakers have filed petitions attesting that their communities have not experienced threats. Furthermore, since the new government was established, calm has returned to Kyiv. There has been no surge in crime, no looting, and no retribution against political opponents.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: Russian bases are under threat.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: Russian military facilities were and remain secure, and the new Ukrainian government has pledged to abide by all existing international agreements, including those covering Russian bases. It is Ukrainian bases in Crimea that are under threat from Russian military action.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: There have been mass attacks on churches and synagogues in southern and eastern Ukraine.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: Religious leaders in the country and international religious freedom advocates active in Ukraine have said there have been no incidents of attacks on churches. All of Ukraine’s church leaders, including representatives of the Ukrainian Orthodox Church-Moscow Patriarchate, have expressed support for the new political leadership, calling for national unity and a period of healing. Jewish groups in southern and eastern Ukraine report that they have not seen an increase in anti-Semitic incidents.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: Kyiv is trying to destabilize Crimea.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: Ukraine’s interim government has acted with restraint and sought dialogue. Russian troops, on the other hand, have moved beyond their bases to seize political objectives and infrastructure in Crimea. The government in Kyiv immediately sent the former Chief of Defense to defuse the situation. Petro Poroshenko, the latest government emissary to pursue dialogue in Crimea, was prevented from entering the Crimean Rada.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mr. Putin says</strong>: The Rada is under the influence of extremists or terrorists.<br/>
<strong>The Facts</strong>: The Rada is the most representative institution in Ukraine. Recent legislation has passed with large majorities, including from representatives of eastern Ukraine. Far-right wing ultranationalist groups, some of which were involved in open clashes with security forces during the EuroMaidan protests, are not represented in the Rada. There is no indication that the Ukrainian government would pursue discriminatory policies; on the contrary, they have publicly stated exactly the opposite.</p></li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<p>We&rsquo;re leaving the conclusions to the readers. You can find the full fact sheet at:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://russian.moscow.usembassy.gov/factsheet-ukraine-03062014.html">http://russian.moscow.usembassy.gov/factsheet-ukraine-03062014.html</a> (Russian)</li>
<li><a href="http://iipdigital.usembassy.gov/st/english/texttrans/2014/03/20140306295487.html#axzz2vJruYOxN">http://iipdigital.usembassy.gov/st/english/texttrans/2014/03/20140306295487.html#axzz2vJruYOxN</a> (English)</li>
</ul>


<p>It didn&rsquo;t take the Russian MFA long to <a href="http://mid.ru/brp_4.nsf/newsline/C48637A3360452D044257C9300518BDD">respond</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>A ministry spokesman, Aleksandr K. Lukashevich, commented on the U.S. Department of State&rsquo;s &ldquo;factual rationales&rdquo; regarding the situation in Ukraine:</strong></p>

<p>The statement &ldquo;disproving&rdquo; the facts mentioned by the President of Russia V. Putin at the press conference on 4th of March about the situation in Ukraine, posted on U.S. Department of State website, is shocking, not as much for its primitive distortion of reality as its cynicism and overt ‘double standards&#8217;.</p>

<p>The State Department is trying to play on a shamelessly one-sided interpretation of events, as if there was not plentiful evidence of atrocities committed by radical nationalists, including the massacre of inconvenient people captured on video cameras, or the murder by provocateur snipers. Washington, of course, can&rsquo;t acknowledge that it nourished &ldquo;Maidan&rdquo; itself, and encouraged the violent overthrow of power, preparing the way for those who now pass themselves off as a legitimate authorities in Kyiv.</p>

<p>We will not stoop as low as to argue with this low-grade propaganda. We will only say that once again we are dealing with unacceptable arrogance and the false assumption of the ultimate truth. The United States doesn’t and can’t have the moral right to lecture us about compliance of international norms. What about the former Yugoslavia bombing or Iraqi invasion under a fabricated motive?</p>

<p>If examining the near distant past, we can find a lot of cases of American military interventions far away from its national borders and without any real threat to the safety of the United States. The Vietnam War claimed two millions of civilians, completely devastated the country, and created a toxic environment. Under the pretense of defending its citizens, that just happened to be in the conflict zone, USA invaded Lebanon in 1958, the Dominican Republic in 1965, attacked tiny Grenada in 1983, bombed Libya in 1986, and three years later occupied Panama. Nevertheless, they dare to reproach Russia for ‘armed aggression’ when she stands up for her countrymen, who constitute the majority of the Crimean people, so as to prevent ultranationalist forces from arranging another bloody &ldquo;Maidan&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Obviously, Washington is still not able to accept the course of events when it contradicts their opinion. They cannot get over it and come to terms with the fact that they cannot always dictate their will and act in their customary role of ‘infallible judge,’ which is followed by — the last word. Their nerves are giving out, but that is no reason to thrust guilt on the innocent.</p>

<p>March 6th, 2014</p></blockquote>

<p>P.S. We now have these cool multi-colored buttons under all our articles. Please click and share!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Cyrillic script being "cancelled"]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/06/cyrillic-cancellation/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-06T15:10:27+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/06/cyrillic-cancellation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s put on some light on the news about the possible abolition of the Cyrillic alphabet on the territory of Ukraine as <a href="http://ria.ru/world/20140305/998301560.html">RIA Novosti claims</a>.</p>

<p>The text of the news says that a special parliamentary commission is working on the law regulating the use of languages ​​in Ukraine and <em>&ldquo;the commission members are trying to use veiled wording in the bill to make a point about the phasing out of the Cyrillic alphabet&rdquo;</em>.</p>

<p>RIA Novosti makes the news on the message from <em>&ldquo;a source familiar with the situation in the Verkhovna Rada (Ukrainian Parliament)&rdquo;</em>. We would like to point out that the text of the news does not provide the exact name of the source and there&rsquo;s no actual evidence by members of the committee (ie, no texts of bills or internal documents) that would contribute to the reliability of the news.  This news was <a href="http://russian.rt.com/article/23696">reprinted by Russia Today</a> along the way giving up the modest word &ldquo;source&rdquo;. However, we already <a href="http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/03/vtoroi-pasport/">put on some attention</a> on the peculiarities of Russia Today&rsquo;s work with information.</p>

<p>Now let&rsquo;s try to understand what is really going on and is there any reason to believe the news and to fear that Ukraine will spend huge money for replacing all the official forms, documents, and street signs.</p>

<p>The Verkhovna Rada website <a href="http://rada.gov.ua/ru/news/Novosty/Soobshchenyya/89017.html">has reported</a> the beginning of the work of the commission. We are providing the version in Russian in case you want to learn more about it (no English version available, sorry!).</p>

<p>According to this report, the range of documents on which the new law is based, includes <a href="http://conventions.coe.int/Treaty/en/Treaties/Html/148.htm">the European Charter for Regional or Minority Languages​​</a>, the Law of Ukraine &ldquo;On ratification of the European Charter for Regional or Minority Languages​​&rdquo; on May 15, 2003, аas well as the well-known <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legislation_on_languages_in_Ukraine">Law of Ukraine &ldquo;On state Language Policy of Ukraine &#8220;dated July 3, 2012</a>, which itself provided the Russian language the status of regional.</p>

<p>But we have not found anything about the replacement of the Cyrillic alphabet with the Latin. As usual, we are not providing any conclusions, but we just want to note that the European Charter of regional languages ​​(by the way, not ratified by Russia) contains the following words at the beginning of the document:</p>

<p><em>protection and promotion of regional or minority languages ​​in different countries and regions of Europe represent an important contribution to the construction of a Europe based on the principles of democracy and cultural diversity within the framework of national sovereignty and territorial integrity</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About the IMF Requirements]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/IMF-debunk/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T22:15:02+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/04/IMF-debunk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s briefly explain the &ldquo;10 IMF Requirements&rdquo;, the acceptance of which is now considered to be <a href="https://www.facebook.com/kostiantyn.stogniy/posts/657506810962958?stream_ref=5">Yatsenyuk&rsquo;s fault</a>.</p>

<p>This piece of &ldquo;breaking news&rdquo; is a bit outdated – it appeared about three years ago. <a href="http://ukranews.com/ru/news/economics/2010/12/07/32810">The Ukrainian News</a> just used an existing analytical article from Hvylya.org dated December 7, 2010. On December 8 a corresponding post <a href="http://hvylya.org/news/digest/wikileaks-15.html">appeared in the Hvylya.org digest</a>, but if you try to follow the links, you&rsquo;ll find out that the pages do not exist.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve found the document on Wikileaks. First of all, they are not &ldquo;obligatory requirements&rdquo;, but just <a href="https://www.wikileaks.org/plusd/cables/10KYIV278_a.html">reform proposals</a>, given by Mr. Pynzenyk, whose name is openly mentioned there, in diplomatic correspondence,</p>

<p>The document is dated February 23, 2010. Let us remind you, how Ukraine cooperated with IMF in that period: in November 2008 the government of Yulia Tymoshenko received an IMF credit in the amount of USD 16.4 billion. In a year the Fund decided to freeze and cancel the credit, but instead of it <a href="http://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/survey/so/2010/car081110a.htm">another credit</a> was given – USD 15.2 billion for the government under the President Yanukovych in July 2010. The second tranche of this credit in the amount of USD 1.5 billion was provided by the IMF Executive Board to Kyiv in December. But then the crediting was suspended, as the program requirements were not being fulfilled with due progress. The government of Yatsenyuk <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/imf-history-with-reneging-ukrainian-leaders-may-cloud-fresh-aid.html">will have to prove</a> the earnestness of their declarations and methods first.</p>

<p>Please see detailed chronology in the following <a href="http://economics.unian.net/other/854861-hronologiya-otnosheniy-ukrainyi-s-mvf.html">UNIAN article</a>. So Pynzenyk&rsquo;s letter was written in the period, when the 2008 credit was already suspended, and the 2010 credit was not being negotiated yet. On December 2013 this text <a href="http://blog.polemika.com.ua/blog/trebovaniy-mvf-ukraine-polnyy-spisok-jlya.html">appeared here</a>, and was readily republished by media. It is a 1:1 reprint of the letter dated 2010.</p>

<p>New IMF requirements haven&rsquo;t been formulated yet, and the existing ones can not be considered obligatory. Make your own conclusions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[USS that couldn't make it]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/george-bush/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T18:06:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/04/george-bush</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may have heard that the U.S. aircraft carrier USS George H. W. Bush was deployed in the direction of Ukraine, you may have even read about it on ICTV&rsquo;s website <a href="http://fakty.ictv.ua/ru/index/read-news/id/1506591">here</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Due to the Russian invasion of the Crimea, the US have sent USS George H. W. Bush in the direction of the Black Sea.</strong></p>

<p>&ldquo;In response to a Russian invasion, the United States has sent an aircraft carrier strike group toward the Black Sea to be able to respond to developments on the Crimean peninsula of Ukraine&rdquo; reports &ldquo;Ukrainian News&rdquo;, citing the Turner Radio Network RSS Feed as the source.</p></blockquote>

<p>We read on the aircraft carrier&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.public.navy.mil/airfor/cvn77/Pages/USS%20GEORGE%20H.W.%20BUSH%20(CVN%2077).aspx">official website</a> that the carrier also has an <a href="http://www.facebook.com/USSGeorgeHWBush">official Facebook page</a>.</p>

<p>After overcoming a fit of laughter at the idea of an aircraft carriers&#8217; crew running an official Facebook page, we read on the page that the ship actually <a href="https://www.facebook.com/notes/uss-george-hw-bush-cvn-77/uss-george-hw-bush-arrives-in-greece/666275313432490">arrived today in Greece</a>.</p>

<p>We send our kind regards to ICTV and the &ldquo;Ukrainian News&rdquo; ;)</p>

<p>By the way, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Montreux_Convention_Regarding_the_Regime_of_the_Straits">Montreux Convention Regarding the Regime of the Straits</a> states that this ship may enter into the Black Sea ONLY when Turkey is at war or if Turkey is under a threat of war. Complete text of Montreux Convention could be read <a href="http://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Montreux_Convention">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2 Girls 1 Fake?]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/03/2-girls-1-fake/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-03T21:21:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/03/2-girls-1-fake</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This evening&rsquo;s sensation was a comparison of two rather viral videos, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Onui6ivzf4o&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=4m">one of which</a> was taken in Kharkov on March 1st (skip to 4:00) and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-OaeZ_mxG4g&amp;feature=player_embedded">the other one</a> in Sevastopol on March 3rd.</p>

<p>Both feature two women demonstrating a definitely pro-Russian rhetoric. First they describe the “mayhem” in Kharkov and then – in the other video – apparently the same women pretend to be Odessa citizens talking about the brutalities of Bandera&rsquo;s followers.Although everyone asserts that these are the same women, we cannot confirm it. We have watched both videos, taken snapshots of the women&rsquo;s faces and asked for the opinions of everyone we could, but could not come to a definite conclusion.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/PeGt0Di.png" alt="EXHIBIT A" /></p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/B7UFIkT.png" alt="EXHIBIT B" />More on this: we have received a video taken by the Crimean channel ATR that <a href="http://atr.ua/video/2014-03-03-15-53-26-2333215">shows a rally</a> in Simferopol featuring a rather similar person (skip to around 6:30). We also have a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;v=T6muI9tIqN0#t=638">video</a> from Odessa; we&rsquo;ll try to compare its soundtrack to that of the Sevastopol video.</p>

<p>You are welcome to make your own conclusions. If you have any relevant materials from the Kharkov, Sevastopol, or Simferopol rallies, please send them to us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second passport]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/03/second-passport/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-03T18:18:12+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/03/second-passport</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We came across the news on the &ldquo;Russia Today&rdquo; channel, a channel that covers more than 644 million people in more than 100 countries, according to <a href="http://rt.com/about-us/">their own information</a>. The news is: <a href="http://russian.rt.com/article/23484">&ldquo;The Verkhovna Rada will introduce criminal liability for dual citizenship&rdquo;</a>.&ldquo;Verkhovna Rada&rdquo; is the name of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verkhovna_Rada">Ukrainian parliament</a></p>

<p>Dear 644 million of people in more than 100 countries! Unfortunately, we have to inform you that you have been deceived. We will not reflect over the reasons, instead we will just demonstrate why this information is false.</p>

<p>Here is what Russia Today saying:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Verkhovna Rada will consider a draft bill regarding criminal liability for dual citizenship after the situation in the country has been stabilised. This law (which provides for a prison sentence of 10 years for dual citizenship) has already been introduced into the Rada.</p></blockquote>

<p>Let’s navigate to <a href="http://rada.gov.ua">Verkhovna Rada official website</a> and find <a href="http://w1.c1.rada.gov.ua/pls/zweb2/webproc4_1?pf3511=49734">the corresponding bill draft</a>. Immediately we see the title:</p>

<blockquote><p>Draft of Law on Amendments to the Criminal Code of Ukraine regarding liability for <strong>failure to inform</strong> about obtaining a foreign citizenship by a citizen of Ukraine.</p></blockquote>

<p>&ldquo;Having dual citizenship&rdquo; vs &ldquo;failure to inform about having dual citizenship&rdquo;. Minor omission, you say?</p>

<p>We could finish our investigation here, but it&rsquo;s way more interesting to dig deeper. So let&rsquo;s open the <a href="http://w1.c1.rada.gov.ua/pls/zweb2/webproc34?id=&amp;pf3511=49734&amp;pf35401=290953">bill draft</a> and take a closer look at its regulations.</p>

<p>Hold on for a second. Let&rsquo;s take a look at original news again.</p>

<blockquote><p>According to the draft introduced into Ukraine&rsquo;s parliament, Ukrainian citizens who receive Russian passports will be fined and sentenced to 3-10 years of prison.</p></blockquote>

<p>And now let&rsquo;s look at the actual draft.</p>

<blockquote><p>Non-submitting or a belated submitting of an application informing about a voluntary acquiring of a foreign citizenship by a Ukrainian citizen of a legal age and of a copy of the document proving his/her acquiring of a foreign citizenship to an authorized body of central executive power is penalized by a fine of 100 minimum non-taxable incomes of citizens.</p></blockquote>

<p>Let&rsquo;s pause here for a second and check current definition of non-taxable minimum income. According to point 5 of chapter 10 of transitional provisions of Ukrainian Tax Code, a non-taxable minimum income is 17 UAH, 100 * 17 = 1700 UAH, a little bit less than 170 USD or 6100 RUR.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the bottom limit of a penal responsibility – 3 years. From the bill draft:</p>

<blockquote><p>The same actions committed by a citizen of Ukraine who <strong>used his/her right to vote</strong> in Ukraine are punishable by imprisonment for a term of 3 to 5 years.</p></blockquote>

<p>And now let&rsquo;s confirm an upper limit &ndash; 10 years. From the bill draft:</p>

<blockquote><p>The same actions, if committed by a citizen of Ukraine who has <strong>access to state secrets</strong>, are punishable by imprisonment for a term of 7 to 10 years.</p></blockquote>

<p>As usual, we won&rsquo;t draw any conclusions. But we note that the Russian Embassy in Ireland is located at a most interesting address: 184-186 Orwell Road, Rathgar, Dublin 14.</p>

<p>And let’s quote this undoubtedly great dystopian.</p>

<blockquote><p>War is peace, freedom is slavery, ignorance is strength.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The call for help from Berkut dormitory is fake]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/02/vberkut-fake/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T21:33:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/02/vberkut-fake</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The only thing worse than false information is attempting to use false information for profit. Fraudsters do not ignore current events. On a lot of online sources you may come across something of following kind:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/o5hXQoD.png" alt="Imgur" />
(<em>phone numbers and Webmoney wallet numbers have been removed for obvious reasons</em>)</p>

<p>There is a translation of the letter above:</p>

<blockquote><p>This is our cry for help! We appeal to all indifferent people and the authorities! We are the families of the &ldquo;Berkut&rdquo; riot police force who live in a dormitory located in the Krasnozvezdniy Prospekt in Kiev. The last few months we have lived in constant fear for us, our husbands and children. Constant threats, bullying, fear have turned our life into a nightmare. Many of us had to quit their jobs and our children have been bullied at school because our husbands have &ldquo;killed people on the Maidan&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Many of us have fled to our relatives, but some have nowhere to go and don&rsquo;t have enough money to flee. The last few days have been absolutely intolerable. All the time there are armed and masked men in front of the dormitory, they are numerous and very aggressive. They don&rsquo;t conceal that they have come to catch Berkut officers. They abuse everyone who enters or leaves the dormitory. They are absolutely unhinged &ndash; yesterday they even beat up the 60-year-old father of one of our women just because he had said something disrespectful about the Maidan. One of our children was walking his dog and these men broke the dog&rsquo;s legs with batons &ndash; and the child saw it all. It&rsquo;s a nightmare!</p>

<p>There are approximately 90 of us left, mostly women, children and older veterans. We also have some wounded young men &ndash; one of them has been badly beaten and had his bones broken, but he is afraid to go to the hospital because our officers are being kidnapped from hospitals.</p>

<p>We can&rsquo;t even ask for help. Some days ago we called the police &ndash; there came two sergeants and three masked men who threatened and abused us in front of our children and the police. We don&rsquo;t have an Internet connection (someone has cut all the cables) and we regularly have blackouts. We are eating up our last food &ndash; the potatoes and pasta that we&rsquo;ve somehow managed to gather.</p>

<p>Yesterday our husbands&#8217; bank cards were blocked &ndash; until the situation is cleared, they said &ndash; and now they&rsquo;re unemployed just for fulfilling their duty, for standing outside at 20 degrees below zero, for being burned and poisoned and shot at&hellip;</p>

<p>We have no more tears left &ndash; our husbands were abused so much, and then betrayed! We had a phone call from Lvov today &ndash; a Berkut officer was killed in his own home because he had been at the Maidan. We don&rsquo;t know whom to trust, how to get help and how to feed our children. If someone could help with accommodation for a few months (also in villages), we would be very grateful. We would also be grateful for anything you could bring to our address, Krasnozvezdniy 152a. Some of us also need money to pay for their mobile connection, we receive a lot of calls and we only have mobile Internet left.</p></blockquote>

<p>We contacted with the 4th Dormitory of GU MVD in Ukraine. Their phone number (044) 524-36-96 is in open access to anyone. We&rsquo;ve been told that they have everything and need no help.</p>

<p>We are also happy to learn, that we are not the only ones, who are critical about emotionally charged information. Users of a <a href="http://forum.sevastopol.info/viewtopic.php?f=11&amp;t=752766&amp;start=375&amp;fb_source=message">Sevastopol forum</a> have also called both the dormitory and the people, whose numbers appeared in the appeal for help. They have also been told, that the dormitory does not need help. Calls to the numbers given in the appeal were either left unanswered or there was no connection whatsoever.</p>

<p>Our conclusion is: this information is fake; it is also an attempt to make money on other people&rsquo;s suffering.</p>

<p>If you really want to donate to a good cause &ndash; donate to «<a href="http://tabletochki.org/welcome">Tabletochki</a>» (the red button that says &ldquo;Apply&rdquo;; it works with all kinds of bank cards). The previous government has decided to spend just 50 million UAH (around 5 million EUR) on children who suffer from cancer, which is 4,5 times less than in 2013 and covers just 20% of the real needs (216 million UAH). &ldquo;Ohmatdit&rdquo; &ndash; the most important clinic for such patients &ndash; has mouldy walls.</p>

<p>We can guarantee the honesty of &ldquo;Tabletochki&rdquo;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazing geography of First channel (Russia)]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/02/first_channel_geography/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T12:06:58+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/02/first_channel_geography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every day brings new reasons to wonder . Today we were absolutely surprised with unique understanding of geography by the &ldquo;Pervyy kanal&rdquo; tv channel in Russia.</p>

<p><img src="http://fakecontrol.org/assets/posts/2014-03-02/poland.jpg" alt="140,000 refugees" /></p>

<p>In the news story &ldquo;More and more Ukraine citizens arrive to the southern Russian regions&rdquo; First Channel claims that</p>

<p>more than 140 000 people crossed the Russian border in the last two weeks. Among them are not only the residents of Ukraine&rsquo;s East and South, but also of central and western regions.</p>

<p>We are ready to believe the fact that inhabitants of western regions cross the border, however it&rsquo;s claimed that people of Ukraine come to &ldquo;Kursk, Belgorod , Rostov and Bryansk regions &rdquo;.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re curious whether Poland is aware that it is the part of Russia. Border crossing point Sheginy (the sign can be seen at 00:14 on the video) is situated in Lviv region and is a checkpoint on the border with Poland.</p>

<p><a href="http://service.alfard-bel.ru/tamogna-online-nehoteevka.html">Webcams</a> also transmit empty roads</p>

<p>The project team hopes that the management of the First Channel will deliver a reprimand to their employees and will force them to love geography &ndash; after all, in a ticklish propaganda and fake business such mistakes are a major failure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Military registration offices have been informed about mobilization]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/02/make-love-not-war/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T03:19:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/02/make-love-not-war</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong> UPD: the statement made by Andriy Parubiy (Secretary of the National Security and Defence Council of Ukraine) at March 2, 2014: </strong> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fK0dLJcZBMM">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fK0dLJcZBMM</a></p>

<p>Once the current post appears on Facebook &ndash; we experienced a lot of mess in comments.
<img src="http://d.pr/i/5BRh+" alt="mob" />
We felt nervous about that so we decided to get in touch with state military registration and enlistment office at Kharkiv. Eventually we&rsquo;ve got following response:</p>

<ul>
<li>Military offices watch the situation and people bother them with calls all the time.</li>
<li>There is no official order regards military mobilization.</li>
<li>The official order is pending signature from The President.</li>
<li>The official order should be advertised on media (at least on national television network).</li>
<li>There is no reason for panic.</li>
</ul>


<p>We have a record of those conversation, but a permission to share was not granted &ndash; so we&rsquo;ve listened to it by ourselves and you have to trust us. Or even better call to your local military office and ask appropriate questions :)</p>

<p>This is the most correct strategy in current situation.</p>

<p>We would not be surprised, if in the morning we will find out that Parubiy&rsquo;s Facebook page was hacked or it&rsquo;s just a fake account, which everybody read by unknown reason.</p>

<p>Please check all the information. Don&rsquo;t be fooled by fakes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About US agents]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/26/us-agent/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-26T12:23:21+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/26/us-agent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SOmpICEfN5o">video on the web</a> (shared couple of days ago) with the following description:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Posted on February 20, 2014.</strong>
American mercenaries fight on Maidan&rsquo;s side. It has been clearly demonstrated by the documents which were seized from the captured soldiers.</p></blockquote>

<p>Below we may find “irrefutable” evidences:</p>

<p><img src="http://d.pr/i/P3qI+" alt="screen1" />
<em>ID Cover</em></p>

<p><img src="http://d.pr/i/IUl5+" alt="screen2" />
<em>The Logo of a certain organization titled IPA</em></p>

<p><img src="http://d.pr/i/AniK+" alt="screen3" />
<em>The ID itself</em></p>

<p>Surprisingly, the police does not know of the existence of <a href="http://www.ipa-ua.org">IPA</a> – an international police organization that Ukraine is a member of.</p>

<blockquote><p>The Ukrainian division of the International Police Association was created on April 25, 1996. In 1997, during the XV World Congress of the IPA in the Canadian city of Quebec, the Ukrainian section gained official recognition in the International Police Association. Today, the IPA comprises of about 8000 members.</p>

<p>Ukrainian IPA section works, consistently putting into practice the primary IPA motto: &ldquo;Serve Through Friendship!&rdquo;. Communication with foreign colleagues, exchange of delegations, common international events &ndash; every activity by the Association members under our country&rsquo;s colors is a contribution of Ukrainian section of IPA to the extension of the professional and friendly relationships between law enforcement officers in different countries, and, eventually, to ensuring peace and friendship on our planet.</p></blockquote>

<p>The scariest part of the story that people blindly believe in such things. They believe in fake images without even checking obvious facts.</p>

<p>Please subscribe to our updates on <a href="http://fb.me/fakecontrol.org">Facebook</a>, ask us any questions you have, and sent tips and links to fake posts – we will check them all, and will publish the most interesting ones.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Portraits on Kyiv City State Administration]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/25/no-hitler/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T19:32:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/25/no-hitler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we found a picture that shows one of the most famous Hitler portraits hanging over the entrance to Kyiv Municipal State Administration. One could laugh, but the image is quickly being shared by Russian trashy websites, low quality personal blogs, local European news sources and social networks.</p>

<p>If you open the image in Adobe Photoshop and apply Rainbow Curve over the image, you may found that the portrait&rsquo;s density is different from the rest of the picture. But this isn’t even necessary, as you can spot the editing with the naked eye.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/cETYhBi.jpg" alt="Imgur" /></p>

<p>Sources: <a href="http://static.uainfo.org/uploads/posts/2014-01/1389709684_1545886_10200332965485265_2019894297_n.jpg">original picture</a>, Google <a href="https://www.google.co.uk/search?client=safari&amp;sa=X&amp;rls=en&amp;q=adolf+hitler&amp;tbm=isch&amp;tbs=simg%3ACAQSYxphCxCo1NgEGgAMCxCwjKcIGjwKOggBEhSqBbYEqwW-BOMErwWuBbAFwQSpBRogwHpodBeHh6Z0XwbkVVvGFoRQZneXyZal915vzEiWiMwMCxCOrv4IGgoKCAgBEgTyI5Y_1DA&amp;ei=9I4MU9qBFuLo7AaF2oGoDw&amp;ved=0CCcQ2A4oAQ&amp;biw=1437&amp;bih=780">search results</a> for fake image.</p>

<p>The original photo can be found if you search for &ldquo;<a href="https://www.google.co.uk/search?client=safari&amp;rls=en&amp;q=%D0%9A%D0%9C%D0%94%D0%90+%D0%BF%D0%BB%D0%B0%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%82&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;gws_rd=cr&amp;ei=PawMU-jADujy7Aaum4GwCw">КМДА плакат</a>&rdquo; (KCSA poster) with the reference to the news story from January, 14th: A portrait of a Bandera, that hung several hours before <a href="http://tsn.ua/kyiv/baner-z-banderoyu-na-kmda-zaminili-na-portret-shevchenka-329493.html">being replaced</a> with a portrait of Taras Shevchenko.</p>

<p>Instead of conclusions, here&rsquo;s the <a href="https://fb.me/fakecontrol.org">link</a> to our Facebook page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Red Cross]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/23/red-cross/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-23T23:27:07+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/red-cross</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Olha Bohomolets in her post <a href="https://www.facebook.com/olgabogomolets/posts/585812244842541">said</a> that the Ukrainian Red Cross Society refused to accept help from the Canadian Red Cross. This information was reposted by <a href="http://www.radiosvoboda.org/content/article/25270523.html">Radio Svoboda</a> and <a href="http://argumentua.com/novosti/ocherednaya-dikost-ukrainskii-krasnyi-krest-otkazalsya-peredat-pomoshch-iz-kanady">Argument</a>) on their pages. But there is an official verification that this information is false!</p>

<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross updated their  Twitter-account with the following <a href="https://twitter.com/ICRC/status/436883171230367744">message</a>
: “Rumour about Ukrainian Red Cross refusing aid from Canadian Red Cross is FALSE. @redcrosscanada didn’t send any official offer for aid.”</p>

<p>It means Canadian Red Cross did not offer their help to Ukranian Red Cross. It would be nice if all involved parts would clarify this issue. And you are welcome to share these news.Thanks a lot,
Fakecontrol Team</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rybak Was Not Attacked]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/23/rybak/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-23T17:27:43+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/rybak</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I believe everyone has read/heard the <a href="http://www.president.gov.ua/ru/news/30127.html">President&rsquo;s statement</a>.</p>

<p>Specifically, there are the following words:&ldquo;Rybak came to me yesterday. While he was on his way to me, the car was fired on. He came to me and asked to take him away. I took him away and sent him to Donetsk by car to have medical treatment.&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=639362169451922"><img src="http://d.pr/i/wCzT+"></a></p>

<p>And today Vladimir Rybak uploaded <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=639362169451922">this video</a>) of him saying is saying that no one ever attempted the life of him.</p>

<p>Enjoy watching, we will refrain from conclusions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrey Vadzhra's Reliable Sources]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/21/vadjra/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-21T16:40:14+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/21/vadjra</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Reliable sources also say that Lubka doesn&rsquo;t say hello, so she must be a slut, and that boyfriend of hers is a junkie!&#8221;These days we&rsquo;ve heard quite a lot about Volodymyr Matvienko&rsquo;s decision to leave the Party of Regions. It is rumoured that he was forced to do so because his child has been kidnapped.</p>

<p>The source of this information is &ldquo;Andrei Vajra, political analyst&rdquo;, as WA REX <a href="http://www.iarex.ru/articles/45411.html">tells us</a> (&ldquo;WA REX is Russian wire agency, not a foreign agent&rdquo;)</p>

<p>Andrey Vadzhra seems to be <a href="http://www.iarex.ru/keywords/601.html">frequently quoted</a>
 by this agency.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had a look at the <a href="http://andreyvadjra.livejournal.com">analyst&rsquo;s blog</a> on LiveJournal and found lots of wonderful stuff.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Today, unknown people broke through a bank&rsquo;s wall and took all the money.&rdquo; Every word is amazing &ndash; just imagine them breaking (!) through a wall (!!!) and escaping with all (!!!) the money! (By the way, this amazing piece of news actually appeared in some Russian media, citing Mr Vadzhra&rsquo;s blog as the source).</p>

<p>&ldquo;Apparently 236 deputies voted for removing riot police from the centre of Kyiv and cancelling the anti-terrorist operation. The chairman, however, did not sign the decree, so it cannot take effect.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s totally strange that a &ldquo;political expert&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t know his own country&rsquo;s legislation. Dear Andrey, should you be reading this, here&rsquo;s an interesting <a href="http://zakon4.rada.gov.ua/laws/show/1861-17">link</a> for you, and <a href="http://vybor.ua/article/zakonotvorchestvo/verhovnaya-rada-ukrainy-20-fevralya-2014.html">here</a> are some excerpts from the respective laws and some expert commentary as well).</p>

<p>&ldquo;Armed skirmishes began between Berkut officers and the &#8220;Right Sector&rdquo; neonazis in the centre of Kyiv. The Verkovna Rada and the Cabinet of Ministers have been evacuated. My sources inform that there is a fight in the Cabinet&rsquo;s building.&ldquo; Well yes, Andrey has the most reliable sources ever.</p>

<p>His <a href="http://andreyvadjra.livejournal.com">LJ blog</a> and <a href="http://alternatio.org/">website</a> are full of this kind of &ldquo;news&rdquo;, they&rsquo;re totally worth looking at.</p>

<p>Do we need to say that it&rsquo;s not easy to believe things said by someone whose sources are SO reliable?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Russian TV]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/20/vesti/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-20T18:42:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/20/vesti</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once again, Russian TV channels distinguished themselves though their coverage of the events in Ukraine. Journalists from Vesti.ru on channel “Russia24” quite accidentally forgot to show the most important and interesting part of <a href="http://www.vesti.ru/only_video.html?vid=578577">the segment</a>.</p>

<p>For your comparison, <a href="http://atn.ua/proisshestviya/kak-izbivali-pod-akademiey-vv-podrobnosti-shturma">here</a> are the same events covered by channel ATN Kharkov.</p>

<p>The urge to attach an old photo posted on the satirical Twitter account dedicated to the work of Dmitry Kiselev is irresistible.</p>

<p><img src="https://scontent-a-lhr.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/t31/1553152_637883049599834_1940260314_o.jpg" alt="kiselev" /></p>

<p><em>Tweet text “So, who are animals here? Maydan bandits stole penguins from the zoo, froze them alive and built barricades with that.“</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
