<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Fake Control]]></title>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-07T01:01:16+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://fakecontrol.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Fake Control Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazing geography of First channel (Russia)]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/02/first_channel_geography/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T10:06:58+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/02/first_channel_geography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every day brings new reasons to wonder . Today we were absolutely surprised with unique understanding of geography by the &ldquo;Pervyy kanal&rdquo; tv channel in Russia.</p>

<p><img src="http://fakecontrol.org/assets/posts/2014-03-02/poland.jpg" alt="140,000 refugees" /></p>

<p>In the news story &ldquo;More and more Ukraine citizens arrive to the southern Russian regions&rdquo; First Channel claims that</p>

<p>more than 140 000 people crossed the Russian border in the last two weeks. Among them are not only the residents of Ukraine&rsquo;s East and South, but also of central and western regions.</p>

<p>We are ready to believe the fact that inhabitants of western regions cross the border, however it&rsquo;s claimed that people of Ukraine come to &ldquo;Kursk, Belgorod , Rostov and Bryansk regions &rdquo;.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re curious whether Poland is aware that it is the part of Russia. Border crossing point Sheginy (the sign can be seen at 00:14 on the video) is situated in Lviv region and is a checkpoint on the border with Poland.</p>

<p><a href="http://service.alfard-bel.ru/tamogna-online-nehoteevka.html">Webcams</a> also transmit empty roads</p>

<p>The project team hopes that the management of the First Channel will deliver a reprimand to their employees and will force them to love geography &ndash; after all, in a ticklish propaganda and fake business such mistakes are a major failure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Portraits on Kyiv City State Administration]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/25/no-hitler/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T17:32:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/25/no-hitler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we found a picture that shows one of the most famous Hitler portraits hanging over the entrance to Kyiv City State Administration (KCSA). One could laugh, but it is being extended to the Russian trash websites, weird blogs, local European news sources and social networks rather quickly.</p>

<p>If you open the image in Adobe Photoshop and apply Rainbow Curve on top, you can see that the portrait density is different from the rest of the picture. But if you look for the original image, it&rsquo;s not even necessary.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/cETYhBi.jpg" alt="Imgur" />Sources: <a href="http://static.uainfo.org/uploads/posts/2014-01/1389709684_1545886_10200332965485265_2019894297_n.jpg">original picture</a>, Google <a href="https://www.google.co.uk/search?client=safari&amp;sa=X&amp;rls=en&amp;q=adolf+hitler&amp;tbm=isch&amp;tbs=simg%3ACAQSYxphCxCo1NgEGgAMCxCwjKcIGjwKOggBEhSqBbYEqwW-BOMErwWuBbAFwQSpBRogwHpodBeHh6Z0XwbkVVvGFoRQZneXyZal915vzEiWiMwMCxCOrv4IGgoKCAgBEgTyI5Y_1DA&amp;ei=9I4MU9qBFuLo7AaF2oGoDw&amp;ved=0CCcQ2A4oAQ&amp;biw=1437&amp;bih=780">search results</a> for fake image.</p>

<p>Original can be found by request &ldquo;<a href="https://www.google.co.uk/search?client=safari&amp;rls=en&amp;q=%D0%9A%D0%9C%D0%94%D0%90+%D0%BF%D0%BB%D0%B0%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%82&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;oe=UTF-8&amp;gws_rd=cr&amp;ei=PawMU-jADujy7Aaum4GwCw">КМДА плакат</a>&rdquo; (KCSA poster) with the reference to the news story from January, 14th: Bandera&rsquo;s portrait that hanged there for several hours <a href="http://tsn.ua/kyiv/baner-z-banderoyu-na-kmda-zaminili-na-portret-shevchenka-329493.html">was replaced</a> with the portrait of Taras Shevchenko.</p>

<p>Instead of conclusions, here&rsquo;s the <a href="https://fb.me/fakecontrol.org">link</a> to our Facebook page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Red Cross]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/23/red-cross/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-23T21:27:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/red-cross</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Olha Bohomolets in her post <a href="https://www.facebook.com/olgabogomolets/posts/585812244842541">said</a> that the Ukrainian Red Cross Society refused to accept help from the Canadian Red Cross. This information was reposted by <a href="http://www.radiosvoboda.org/content/article/25270523.html">Radio Svoboda</a> and <a href="http://argumentua.com/novosti/ocherednaya-dikost-ukrainskii-krasnyi-krest-otkazalsya-peredat-pomoshch-iz-kanady">Argument</a>) on their pages. But there is an official verification that this information is false!</p>

<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross updated their  Twitter-account with the following <a href="https://twitter.com/ICRC/status/436883171230367744">message</a>
: “Rumour about Ukrainian Red Cross refusing aid from Canadian Red Cross is FALSE. @redcrosscanada didn’t send any official offer for aid.”</p>

<p>It means Canadian Red Cross did not offer their help to Ukranian Red Cross. It would be nice if all involved parts would clarify this issue. And you are welcome to share these news.Thanks a lot,
Fakecontrol Team</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rybak Was Not Attacked]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/23/rybak/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-23T15:27:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/rybak</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I believe everyone has read/heard the <a href="http://www.president.gov.ua/ru/news/30127.html">President&rsquo;s statement</a>.</p>

<p>Specifically, there are the following words:&ldquo;Rybak came to me yesterday. While he was on his way to me, the car was fired on. He came to me and asked to take him away. I took him away and sent him to Donetsk by car to have medical treatment.&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=639362169451922"><img src="http://d.pr/i/wCzT+"></a></p>

<p>And today Vladimir Rybak uploaded <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=639362169451922">this video</a>) of him saying is saying that no one ever attempted the life of him.</p>

<p>Enjoy watching, we will refrain from conclusions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrey Vadzhra's Reliable Sources]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/21/vadjra/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-21T14:40:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/21/vadjra</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Reliable sources also say that Lubka doesn&rsquo;t say hello, so she must be a slut, and that boyfriend of hers is a junkie!&#8221;These days we&rsquo;ve heard quite a lot about Volodymyr Matvienko&rsquo;s decision to leave the Party of Regions. It is rumoured that he was forced to do so because his child has been kidnapped.</p>

<p>The source of this information is &ldquo;Andrei Vajra, political analyst&rdquo;, as WA REX <a href="http://www.iarex.ru/articles/45411.html">tells us</a> (&ldquo;WA REX is Russian wire agency, not a foreign agent&rdquo;)</p>

<p>Andrey Vadzhra seems to be <a href="http://www.iarex.ru/keywords/601.html">frequently quoted</a>
 by this agency.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had a look at the <a href="http://andreyvadjra.livejournal.com">analyst&rsquo;s blog</a> on LiveJournal and found lots of wonderful stuff.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Today, unknown people broke through a bank&rsquo;s wall and took all the money.&rdquo; Every word is amazing &ndash; just imagine them breaking (!) through a wall (!!!) and escaping with all (!!!) the money! (By the way, this amazing piece of news actually appeared in some Russian media, citing Mr Vadzhra&rsquo;s blog as the source).</p>

<p>&ldquo;Apparently 236 deputies voted for removing riot police from the centre of Kyiv and cancelling the anti-terrorist operation. The chairman, however, did not sign the decree, so it cannot take effect.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s totally strange that a &ldquo;political expert&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t know his own country&rsquo;s legislation. Dear Andrey, should you be reading this, here&rsquo;s an interesting <a href="http://zakon4.rada.gov.ua/laws/show/1861-17">link</a> for you, and <a href="http://vybor.ua/article/zakonotvorchestvo/verhovnaya-rada-ukrainy-20-fevralya-2014.html">here</a> are some excerpts from the respective laws and some expert commentary as well).</p>

<p>&ldquo;Armed skirmishes began between Berkut officers and the &#8220;Right Sector&rdquo; neonazis in the centre of Kyiv. The Verkovna Rada and the Cabinet of Ministers have been evacuated. My sources inform that there is a fight in the Cabinet&rsquo;s building.&ldquo; Well yes, Andrey has the most reliable sources ever.</p>

<p>His <a href="http://andreyvadjra.livejournal.com">LJ blog</a> and <a href="http://alternatio.org/">website</a> are full of this kind of &ldquo;news&rdquo;, they&rsquo;re totally worth looking at.</p>

<p>Do we need to say that it&rsquo;s not easy to believe things said by someone whose sources are SO reliable?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Russian TV]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/02/20/vesti/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-20T16:42:11+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/20/vesti</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once again, Russian TV channels distinguished themselves though their coverage of the events in Ukraine. Journalists from Vesti.ru on channel “Russia24” quite accidentally forgot to show the most important and interesting part of <a href="http://www.vesti.ru/only_video.html?vid=578577">the segment</a>.</p>

<p>For your comparison, <a href="http://atn.ua/proisshestviya/kak-izbivali-pod-akademiey-vv-podrobnosti-shturma">here</a> are the same events covered by channel ATN Kharkov.</p>

<p>The urge to attach an old photo posted on the satirical Twitter account dedicated to the work of Dmitry Kiselev is irresistible.</p>

<p><img src="https://scontent-a-lhr.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/t31/1553152_637883049599834_1940260314_o.jpg" alt="kiselev" /></p>

<p><em>Tweet text “So, who are animals here? Maydan bandits stole penguins from the zoo, froze them alive and built barricades with that.“</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
