<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: en | Fake Control]]></title>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/categories/en/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-13T15:01:36+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://fakecontrol.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Fake Control Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The fake prohibition of celebrating the holidays]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/13/holidays/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-13T15:01:36+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/13/holidays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One more <a href="http://www.gorodche.ru/news/society/30171/">news from Rada</a> (Ukrainian Parliament) turned out to be fake, or, to be more precise, an incorrect interpretation of the just adopted regulations.</p>

<p>In particular, the journalists of the mentioned news provider reckon, that the decision based on the Cabinet of Ministers of Ukraine Regulation №65 dated 1/03/2014 rules the following:</p>

<blockquote><p>Fairs, festivals, conventions, celebrating commemorative and historical dates, Victory Day, Constitution Day, Independence Day and the Day of commemoration of Holodomors victims are also banned.</p></blockquote>

<p>Let&rsquo;s refer to <a href="http://zakon2.rada.gov.ua/laws/show/65-2014-%D0%BF">the text of the regulation</a>, namely to the clause regarding the holidays, which will speak for itself:</p>

<blockquote><p>20 Suspension of the use of budgetary funds for running events related to celebrating commemorative and historical dates, anniversaries of enterprises, institutions and organizations, along with anniversaries and commemoration of prominent figures and other events (except centralized Ministry of Culture events for celebrating 200 years from the day of birth of Taras Shevchenko, Constitution Day, Independence Day, Victory Day, Day of commemoration of Holodomors victims), printing production not related to exercise of functions of governmental authorities.</p></blockquote>

<p>Obviously, nobody banned celebrating Victory Day, Constitution Day, Independence Day and the Day of commemoration of Holodomors victims.</p>

<p>The conclusions, as usual, are up to you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The e-mails of Igor Protsyk]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/13/anon-fake-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-13T03:24:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/13/anon-fake-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are being aggressively offered to believe another sensation from an allegedly hacked mailbox. This time the &ldquo;data leak&rdquo; has been presented as follows:</p>

<p><em>We have hacked e-mail correspondence of US Army Attache Assistant in Kiev Jason Gresh and a high ranking official from Ukrainian General Staff Igor Protsyk</em>.</p>

<p>An archive of messages, allegedly from the <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code> mailbox, was <a href="http://www.sendspace.com/file/ih96tx">published</a>. The package contains two folders – &ldquo;most interesting&rdquo; with three scandalous e-mails, which have been spread all over the Internet, and &ldquo;all&rdquo; with the complete archive of 86 messages.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve analyzed the &ldquo;all&rdquo; folder and would like to make the following statements on the three &ldquo;most interesting&rdquo; messages:</p>

<p><strong>E-mail #1</strong>: from <code>GreshJP@state.gov</code> to <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code>, delivered on 9 Mar 2014 08:57:15 -0700.</p>

<p>It looks very different from the rest five messages between the same users (<code>GreshJP@state.gov</code> to <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code>) in the &ldquo;all&rdquo; folder (an obvious difference in English skills is just one of them). For example, all the content of this message belongs to the &ldquo;text/plain&rdquo; data type (the other ones are multipart/related, with HTML part). Besides that, this message does not end with the notice &ldquo;SBU This email is UNCLASSIFIED&rdquo; (SBU, Sensitive But Unclassified – a designation of information in the United States government).</p>

<p><strong>E-mail #2</strong>: from <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code> to <code>krivonis.te@gmail.com</code>, delivered on 11 Mar 2014 05:50:36 -0700.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/V7ZoaGa.png" alt="Imgur" /></p>

<p>This message, unlike all the other archived ones sent by <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code>, has a valid DKIM-signature and headers confirming its delivery to <code>krivonis.te@gmail.com</code>. The presence of those headers makes it clear that the message was extracted from the <code>krivonis.te@gmail.com</code> mailbox, not from <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code> (that is from the recipient mailbox, though the archive has nothing to do with it).</p>

<p>That means that the hackers had access not only to the mailbox of <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code>, but also to <code>krivonis.te@gmail.com</code>; that&rsquo;s true for E-mail #3 as well.</p>

<p><strong><em>E-mail #3</em></strong>: from <code>krivonis.te@gmail.com</code> to <code>kolyarny@gmail.com</code> (by the way, the latter mailbox can be found on the Web only in the context of the &ldquo;data leak&rdquo; in question) and to <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code>, delivered on 11 Mar 2014 09:20:47 -0700.</p>

<p>Besides that the archive contains a message from <code>no-reply@accounts.google.com</code> to <code>protsyk@ukr.net</code> with password recovery information, delivered on 11 Mar 2014 05:47:11 -0700 (before sending of E-mails #2 and #3). Judging by the fact that there are 21 more e-mails to <code>protsyk@ukr.net</code> in the archive, the messages from that address are being forwarded to <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code>.</p>

<p>You are free to make your own conclusions, but here are some hints from us:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>The hackers declared that they had access to the <code>GreshJP@state.gov</code> and <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code> mailboxes. But all the published messages between these two addresses are obviously not trustworthy, as they could have been written by the hackers themselves. The hackers most likely had no access to <code>GreshJP@state.gov</code>, because E-mail #1 was clumsily forged on the basis of the rest five &ldquo;legitimate&rdquo; messages from <code>GreshJP@state.gov</code> found in the <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code> mailbox.</p></li>
<li><p>The message from <code>no-reply@accounts.google.com</code> gives us reasons to suppose that E-mails #2 and #3 have been sent after the <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code> mailbox was compromised; that means that those e-mails could have been sent by the hackers themselves.</p></li>
<li><p>E-mail #2 proves that the hackers had access to <code>krivonis.te@gmail.com</code>, so why couldn&rsquo;t E-mail #3 have been created by the hackers?</p></li>
</ol>


<p>This time the &ldquo;Anonymous Ukraine&rdquo; authors of the mail hacking scandal concerning the Crimea provocations made a <a href="http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/02/anon-fake/">far less clumsy try</a>. The <a href="http://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/DomainKeys_Identified_Mail">DKIM-signatures</a> are doubtlessly proving the hacking of the <code>igor.protsyk@gmail.com</code> and <code>krivonis.te@gmail.com</code> mailboxes. But the results of the comparison between the &ldquo;alarming&rdquo; and all the other archived messages suggest with a high probability that the e-mails, which have so providently been placed in a separate directory under the meaningful name &ldquo;most interesting&rdquo;, have been forged or sent by the hackers themselves.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About «Order of the Russian Federation Government»]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/12/ob-ukazah-pravitelstva-rf/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T14:06:01+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/12/ob-ukazah-pravitelstva-rf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This one of the shortest posts ever: order № 303/14р, allegedly signed by Medvedev on March 1, <em>does not exist</em> in the <a href="http://government.consultant.ru">database</a> of &ldquo;Regulatory Documents of the Russian Federation Government&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/BNMzvzt.png" alt="303/14-fake" /></p>

<p>Translation of the image above:</p>

<blockquote><p>Government of the Russian Federation
Order from March 1, 2014 № 303/14р</p>

<p>Moscow</p>

<p>Agree on a draft of a state program for Trans-Baikal, Kamchatka and Primorye Territories about the &ldquo;Assistance in resettlement to Trans-Baikal, Kamchatka, and the Primorsky Region of compatriots currently residing in the new subjects of the Russian Federation, in particular, in the Autonomous Republic of Crimea, Odessa, Kherson, Nikolae, Donetsk, Luhansk and Kharkiv regions for 2014-2016 years&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Prime Minister of the Russian Federation
Dmitry Medvedev</p></blockquote>

<p>You can make sure yourself by checking the search results for the March 1</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Merkel, Klitschko, Tymoshenko... and all the rest involved]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/08/merkel-klitchko-timoshenko/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-08T14:21:44+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/08/merkel-klitchko-timoshenko</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Friday, March 7, the official website of Batkivshchyna (Yulia Tymoshenko&rsquo;s political party) <a href="http://batkivshchyna.com.ua/news/open/1059">informed</a> its readers about the meeting between Tymoshenko and Angela Merkel.</p>

<p>We don&rsquo;t want you to be confused about the meeting&rsquo;s scope and participants, so we&rsquo;ll add just two small details to this piece of <a href="news:">news:</a></p>

<ol>
<li><p>This was a collective event with the participation of Vitali Klitschko, Yulia Tymoshenko and Angela Merkel, not a one-on-one meeting between two major politicians, as some people are trying to present it. Do you want a proof? Here you are: a <a href="https://twitter.com/RegSprecher/status/441916443995553793/photo/1">tweet</a> of Steffen Seibert (the German Chancellor&rsquo;s press-secretary).</p></li>
<li><p>It was a short talk along the lines of summit – here&rsquo;s Stern&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.stern.de/politik/ausland/ukraine-krise-prorussische-kaempfer-stuermen-armeebasis-auf-der-krim-2094923.html">report</a> about it, and here are <a href="https://www.facebook.com/trinitycollegedublin/posts/828271160521319?stream_ref=10">some pictures</a> from the Trinity College of Dublin, where Merkel gave a speech about &ldquo;globalized Europe&rdquo; after the event.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Many Ukrainian media have already republished the photo from Tymoshenko&rsquo;s party website. It&rsquo;s a pity that the situation is being completely and deliberately misinterpreted. The fact is that Merkel met two representatives of Ukrainian political parties during the Dublin summit, to which she invited them herself. Instead of that some people try to convince us that &ldquo;Yulia is a strong politician, and even Merkel finds some time in her schedule to talk to her&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t act that way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Its all about language, again]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/08/tass-upolnomochien-zaiavit/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-08T10:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/08/tass-upolnomochien-zaiavit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We would like to give up walking on the thin ice of the language problem, but our beloved media does not let us to do so. At this time, the reader put on the alarm sending us a completely unbelievable <a href="http://itar-tass.com/mezhdunarodnaya-panorama/1029332">news</a> that the Administration of acting President of Ukraine Turchynov ordered to remove Russian-language versions of the official websites of public authorities. Perhaps we analyze the news thoroughly.</p>

<blockquote><p>KIEV, March 7. / ITAR-TASS /. Administration of appointed by the Verkhovna Rada Acting President of Ukraine Oleksandr Turchynov has ordered to the Ukrainian bodies of state power to enable Russian-language versions of their official websites, as the source in the Cabinet of Ministers reports to ITAR-TASS .</p></blockquote>

<p>So, the first thing that can cause some doubts. Unknown &ldquo;source&rdquo; reports &ndash; as if about an already made decision, consequently, there is no sence for this source to hide. Our inner barometer automatically moved a pointer to the section &ldquo;fake&rdquo;.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Until March 10 all Ukrainian executive, legislative and judicial state authorities must block the access to the Russian versions of their official websites,&rdquo; &ndash; he said. According to the source, the Russian versions of internet pages of 14 key ministries are eliminated by now: the Ministry of Health, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Ministry of Defense, Ministry of Finance, Ministry of Industry, Ministry of Social Policy and others, as well as web portals of the Supreme Court and the Supreme Economic Court of Ukraine.</p></blockquote>

<p>Oh, a mysterious source didn&rsquo;t take into account that it is quite easy to check such order. We will use <a href="http://archive.org/web/">Internet Wayback Machine</a> service. It will be fun!</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.moz.gov.ua/ua/portal/">Ministry of Health</a>. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130813113040/http://www.moz.gov.ua/ua/portal/">As of August 13, 2013</a> not only Russian version is absent, but so is the English one. It hasn&rsquo;t changed since then.</li>
<li><a href="http://mfa.gov.ua/ua">Ministry of Foreign Affairs</a>. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130816001321/http://mfa.gov.ua/ua">As of August 16, 2013</a> only Ukrainian and English versions are available. It hasn&rsquo;t changed since then.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mil.gov.ua/">Ministry of Defense</a>. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130801033533/http://www.mil.gov.ua/">As of August 1, 2013</a> Russian version is in the website header and it works. Now it&rsquo;s still in the header, but doesn&rsquo;t work. We can&rsquo;t assert, but we think it&rsquo;s connected to the current events, and is generally predictable.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.minfin.gov.ua/control/ru/index">Ministry of Finance</a> &ndash; we&rsquo;ll just leave the link to the Russian version for ITAR-TASS here.</li>
<li><a href="http://industry.gov.ua">Ministry of Industry</a>. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140214045904/http://industry.gov.ua/">As of February 14, 2014</a> Russian and English versions are available. The same as now.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mlsp.gov.ua">Ministry of Social Policy</a>. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130809060550/http://www.mlsp.gov.ua/labour/control/uk/index">As of August 9, 2013</a>  the link to the Russian version in the header is missing, but it can be found by replacing <code>uk</code> with <code>ru</code> in the URL. However, this version is still empty, as well as in the archive.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.scourt.gov.ua/">Supreme Court</a>. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130823191633/http://www.scourt.gov.ua/">As of 23 of August 2013</a> &ndash; only ukrainian and english versions are available.</li>
<li><a href="http://vgsu.arbitr.gov.ua/">Superior commercial court</a>. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130815204613/http://vgsu.arbitr.gov.ua/">As of 15 of August 2013</a> &ndash; only ukrainian and english versions are available.</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Moreover, the Russian language has disappeared from the official web pages of central executive bodies of special status: the Security Service, the Antimonopoly Committee, etc.,&rdquo; &ndash; the source added.</p></blockquote>

<p>The same applies to the Security Service and the Antimonopoly Committee &ndash; Russian version either exists or there was no before.</p>

<p>We have got two questions on this subject.</p>

<p>First, the Ministry of Finance, for how long will you neglect the order of <em>Acting President</em> (a fake one)? Boo, saboteurs!</p>

<p>The second one requires a <a href="http://itar-tass.com/pages/tass-today">quotation</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Nowadays, the amount of information produced in the world is growing exponentially, so the question of its authenticity becomes acute. It is therefore of paramount importance to ITAR-TASS team the authenticity of the information received by our subscribers.</p></blockquote>

<p>Hey ITAR-TASS (The Information Telegraph Agency of Russia), shame on you!</p>

<p>P.S. The one, who would find the Russian versions of the above mentioned pages, will get a beautiful picture a of pug from us for free!</p>

<p><strong>Update</strong>: &ldquo;News&rdquo; by ITAR-TASS, seems to be picked up by everybody including the Echo of Moscow, Kommersant and RT:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.echo.msk.ru/news/1274556-echo.html">http://www.echo.msk.ru/news/1274556-echo.html</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.kommersant.ru/doc/2425851">http://www.kommersant.ru/doc/2425851</a></li>
<li><a href="http://russian.rt.com/article/23878">http://russian.rt.com/article/23878</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
