<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: _i18n | Fake Control]]></title>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/categories/i18n/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-07T15:57:42+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://fakecontrol.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Fake Control Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we've been doing?]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/07/digest/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-07T15:57:42+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/07/digest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[While you were working for the good of your country and family, we were checking news for you, like we always do. And then we checked them all. And then we decided — hey, why not make a digest for every person who might have missed an article or two.
And here we go! 

### [2 Girls, 1 Fake](http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/03/2-girls-1-fake/)
Two women, who cry constantly and pray for Putin the Savior to come and, ahem, save them, turned out to be a lot more than just crying women. Changing cities, names and stories on daily basis, these two had a fabulous tour around Ukraine. We talk about their identities and get some very interesting comments from dentists and plastic surgeons. That may be the first time you read non-toxic comments so be aware!

### [Second passport, Third Sentence](http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/03/second-passport/)
Our all time favourite, Russia Today. They've been saying lately that having more than one citizenship may become punishable by criminal penalty. We tried hard to overcome our hysterical laughing and managed to tell you all why all that is just totally wrong.

### [USS That Couldn't Make It](http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/george-bush/)
A breathtaking story of George H. W. Bush aircraft carrier which never managed to get to the Crimea and instead just chilled in Greece. Besides explaining what is what, we send greeting to the team of Ukrainian TV channel ICTV and suggest that you should read Montreux Convention Regarding the Regime of the Straits. It's fun reading, we promise!

### [About IMF "requirements"](http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/IMF-debunk/)
Your parents must've told you about crazy mortage payments and the disbandment of free education for your (hypothetical)kids. All that is IMF's fault! Except it's not and your parents were fooled, which we talk about a lot in our article. Anyway, are you really that sure you're ready to have kids?

### [About Cyrillic script being "cancelled"](http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/06/cyrillic-cancellation/)
The piece of news without reliable source in it is totally okay to post at one of the biggest news agencies site, right? We did not think so too! Latin alphabet is no cakewalk to suddenly start to use, especially in a country which was using Cyrillic script for many centuries. Fun historical facts as Friday bonus!

---

You can find more at our [site](http://fakecontrol.org/en/) or [Facebook page](https://www.facebook.com/fakecontrol.org).

If you want to send us important news or just want to share a picture of a cute pug, [tweet us](https://twitter.com/fakecontrol_org) or send us an [email](team@fakecontrol.org)!
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Cyrillic script being "cancelled"]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/06/cyrillic-cancellation/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-06T15:10:27+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/06/cyrillic-cancellation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Let's put on some light on the news about the possible abolition of the Cyrillic alphabet on the territory of Ukraine as [RIA Novosti claims](http://ria.ru/world/20140305/998301560.html).

The text of the news says that a special parliamentary commission is working on the law regulating the use of languages ​​in Ukraine and _"the commission members are trying to use veiled wording in the bill to make a point about the phasing out of the Cyrillic alphabet"_.

RIA Novosti makes the news on the message from _"a source familiar with the situation in the Verkhovna Rada (Ukrainian Parliament)"_. We would like to point out that the text of the news does not provide the exact name of the source and there's no actual evidence by members of the committee (ie, no texts of bills or internal documents) that would contribute to the reliability of the news.  This news was [reprinted by Russia Today](http://russian.rt.com/article/23696) along the way giving up the modest word "source". However, we already [put on some attention](/blog/2014/03/03/vtoroi-pasport/) on the peculiarities of Russia Today's work with information.

Now let's try to understand what is really going on and is there any reason to believe the news and to fear that Ukraine will spend huge money for replacing all the official forms, documents, and street signs.

The Verkhovna Rada website [has reported](http://rada.gov.ua/ru/news/Novosty/Soobshchenyya/89017.html) the beginning of the work of the commission. We are providing the version in Russian in case you want to learn more about it (no English version available, sorry!).

According to this report, the range of documents on which the new law is based, includes [the European Charter for Regional or Minority Languages​​](http://conventions.coe.int/Treaty/en/Treaties/Html/148.htm), the Law of Ukraine "On ratification of the European Charter for Regional or Minority Languages​​" on May 15, 2003, аas well as the well-known [Law of Ukraine "On state Language Policy of Ukraine "dated July 3, 2012](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legislation_on_languages_in_Ukraine), which itself provided the Russian language the status of regional.

But we have not found anything about the replacement of the Cyrillic alphabet with the Latin. As usual, we are not providing any conclusions, but we just want to note that the European Charter of regional languages ​​(by the way, not ratified by Russia) contains the following words at the beginning of the document:

_protection and promotion of regional or minority languages ​​in different countries and regions of Europe represent an important contribution to the construction of a Europe based on the principles of democracy and cultural diversity within the framework of national sovereignty and territorial integrity_.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About the IMF Requirements]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/IMF-debunk/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T22:15:02+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/04/IMF-debunk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Let's briefly explain the "10 IMF Requirements", the acceptance of which is now considered to be [Yatsenyuk's fault](https://www.facebook.com/kostiantyn.stogniy/posts/657506810962958?stream_ref=5).

This piece of "breaking news" is a bit outdated – it appeared about three years ago. [The Ukrainian News](http://ukranews.com/ru/news/economics/2010/12/07/32810) just used an existing analytical article from Hvylya.org dated December 7, 2010. On December 8 a corresponding post [appeared in the Hvylya.org digest](http://hvylya.org/news/digest/wikileaks-15.html), but if you try to follow the links, you'll find out that the pages do not exist.

We've found the document on Wikileaks. First of all, they are not "obligatory requirements", but just [reform proposals](https://www.wikileaks.org/plusd/cables/10KYIV278_a.html), given by Mr. Pynzenyk, whose name is openly mentioned there, in diplomatic correspondence,

The document is dated February 23, 2010. Let us remind you, how Ukraine cooperated with IMF in that period: in November 2008 the government of Yulia Tymoshenko received an IMF credit in the amount of USD 16.4 billion. In a year the Fund decided to freeze and cancel the credit, but instead of it [another credit](http://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/survey/so/2010/car081110a.htm) was given – USD 15.2 billion for the government under the President Yanukovych in July 2010. The second tranche of this credit in the amount of USD 1.5 billion was provided by the IMF Executive Board to Kyiv in December. But then the crediting was suspended, as the program requirements were not being fulfilled with due progress. The government of Yatsenyuk [will have to prove](http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/imf-history-with-reneging-ukrainian-leaders-may-cloud-fresh-aid.html) the earnestness of their declarations and methods first.

Please see detailed chronology in the following [UNIAN article](http://economics.unian.net/other/854861-hronologiya-otnosheniy-ukrainyi-s-mvf.html). So Pynzenyk's letter was written in the period, when the 2008 credit was already suspended, and the 2010 credit was not being negotiated yet. On December 2013 this text [appeared here](http://blog.polemika.com.ua/blog/trebovaniy-mvf-ukraine-polnyy-spisok-jlya.html), and was readily republished by media. It is a 1:1 reprint of the letter dated 2010.

New IMF requirements haven't been formulated yet, and the existing ones can not be considered obligatory. Make your own conclusions.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[USS that couldn't make it]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/04/george-bush/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T18:06:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/04/george-bush</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[You may have heard that the U.S. aircraft carrier USS George H. W. Bush was deployed in the direction of Ukraine, you may have even read about it on ICTV's website [here](http://fakty.ictv.ua/ru/index/read-news/id/1506591):

> **Due to the Russian invasion of the Crimea, the US have sent USS George H. W. Bush in the direction of the Black Sea.**
>
> "In response to a Russian invasion, the United States has sent an aircraft carrier strike group toward the Black Sea to be able to respond to developments on the Crimean peninsula of Ukraine" reports "Ukrainian News", citing the Turner Radio Network RSS Feed as the source.

We read on the aircraft carrier's <a href="http://www.public.navy.mil/airfor/cvn77/Pages/USS%20GEORGE%20H.W.%20BUSH%20(CVN%2077).aspx">official website</a> that the carrier also has an [official Facebook page](http://www.facebook.com/USSGeorgeHWBush).

After overcoming a fit of laughter at the idea of an aircraft carriers' crew running an official Facebook page, we read on the page that the ship actually [arrived today in Greece](https://www.facebook.com/notes/uss-george-hw-bush-cvn-77/uss-george-hw-bush-arrives-in-greece/666275313432490).

We send our kind regards to ICTV and the "Ukrainian News" ;)

By the way, the [Montreux Convention Regarding the Regime of the Straits](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Montreux_Convention_Regarding_the_Regime_of_the_Straits) states that this ship may enter into the Black Sea ONLY when Turkey is at war or if Turkey is under a threat of war. Complete text of Montreux Convention could be read [here](http://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Montreux_Convention).]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2 Girls 1 Fake?]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/en/blog/2014/03/03/2-girls-1-fake/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-03T21:21:39+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/03/2-girls-1-fake</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[This evening's sensation was a comparison of two rather viral videos, [one of which](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Onui6ivzf4o&feature=youtu.be&t=4m) was taken in Kharkov on March 1st (skip to 4:00) and [the other one](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-OaeZ_mxG4g&feature=player_embedded) in Sevastopol on March 3rd. Both feature two women demonstrating a definitely pro-Russian rhetoric. First they describe the “mayhem” in Kharkov and then – in the other video – apparently the same women pretend to be Odessa citizens talking about the brutalities of Bandera's followers.Although everyone asserts that these are the same women, we cannot confirm it. We have watched both videos, taken snapshots of the women's faces and asked for the opinions of everyone we could, but could not come to a definite conclusion.


![EXHIBIT A](http://i.imgur.com/PeGt0Di.png)

![EXHIBIT B](http://i.imgur.com/B7UFIkT.png)More on this: we have received a video taken by the Crimean channel ATR that [shows a rally]http://atr.ua/video/2014-03-03-15-53-26-2333215) in Simferopol featuring a rather similar person (skip to around 6:30). We also have a [video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&v=T6muI9tIqN0#t=638) from Odessa; we'll try to compare its soundtrack to that of the Sevastopol video.You are welcome to make your own conclusions. If you have any relevant materials from the Kharkov, Sevastopol, or Simferopol rallies, please send them to us.]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
