<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: _i18n | Fake Control]]></title>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/blog/categories/i18n/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-06T15:41:58-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://fakecontrol.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Fake Control Team]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazing geography of First channel (Russia)]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/02/first_channel_geography/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T02:06:58-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/03/02/first_channel_geography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every day brings new reasons to wonder . Today we were absolutely surprised with unique understanding of geography by the &ldquo;Pervyy kanal&rdquo; tv channel in Russia.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/posts/2014-03-02/poland.jpg" alt="140,000 refugees" /></p>

<p>In the news story &ldquo;More and more Ukraine citizens arrive to the southern Russian regions&rdquo; First Channel claims that</p>

<p>more than 140 000 people crossed the Russian border in the last two weeks. Among them are not only the residents of Ukraine&rsquo;s East and South, but also of central and western regions.</p>

<p>We are ready to believe the fact that inhabitants of western regions cross the border, however it&rsquo;s claimed that people of Ukraine come to &ldquo;Kursk, Belgorod , Rostov and Bryansk regions &rdquo;.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re curious whether Poland is aware that it is the part of Russia. Border crossing point Sheginy (the sign can be seen at 00:14 on the video) is situated in Lviv region and is a checkpoint on the border with Poland.</p>

<p><a href="http://service.alfard-bel.ru/tamogna-online-nehoteevka.html">Webcams</a> also transmit empty roads</p>

<p>The project team hopes that the management of the First Channel will deliver a reprimand to their employees and will force them to love geography &ndash; after all, in a ticklish propaganda and fake business such mistakes are a major failure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Red Cross]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/red-cross/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-23T13:27:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/red-cross</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Olha Bohomolets in her post <a href="https://www.facebook.com/olgabogomolets/posts/585812244842541">said</a> that the Ukrainian Red Cross Society refused to accept help from the Canadian Red Cross. This information was reposted by <a href="http://www.radiosvoboda.org/content/article/25270523.html">Radio Svoboda</a> and <a href="http://argumentua.com/novosti/ocherednaya-dikost-ukrainskii-krasnyi-krest-otkazalsya-peredat-pomoshch-iz-kanady">Argument</a>) on their pages. But there is an official verification that this information is false!</p>

<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross updated their  Twitter-account with the following <a href="https://twitter.com/ICRC/status/436883171230367744">message</a>
: “Rumour about Ukrainian Red Cross refusing aid from Canadian Red Cross is FALSE. @redcrosscanada didn’t send any official offer for aid.”</p>

<p>It means Canadian Red Cross did not offer their help to Ukranian Red Cross. It would be nice if all involved parts would clarify this issue. And you are welcome to share these news.Thanks a lot,Fakecontrol Team</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rybak Was Not Attacked]]></title>
    <link href="http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/rybak/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-23T07:27:43-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://fakecontrol.org/blog/2014/02/23/rybak</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I believe everyone has read/heard the <a href="http://www.president.gov.ua/ru/news/30127.html">President&rsquo;s statement</a>.
Specifically, there are the following words:&ldquo;Rybak came to me yesterday. While he was on his way to me, the car was fired on. He came to me and asked to take him away. I took him away and sent him to Donetsk by car to have medical treatment.&rdquo;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=639362169451922"><img src="http://d.pr/i/wCzT+"></a>
And today Vladimir Rybak uploaded <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=639362169451922">this video</a>) of him saying is saying that no one ever attempted the life of him.Enjoy watching, we will refrain from conclusions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
